It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
어지러운 전국 시대.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
Musashi is here-dasu!
무사시 등장이오!
Karakuri Kengouden
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
A man always dreams of the day
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
in the center of the world to become
제일 강해질 날을
AH! AH! the strongest
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
모험의 길의 막을 연다
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
Go! Fight!
가라! 싸워라!
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
Tomorrow will be glorious
내일은 빛난다
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Fight the utmost with the stillness
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
His eyes shined! Musashi!
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
Musashi fell into Shiranui's trap, and was paralyzed by poison.
시라누이의 함정에 빠진 무사시는 독 때문에 마비되고 말았다.
And Kojirō got his beloved sword Monohoshizao broken, and fell into the very bottom of despair.
그리고 코지로는 애도 모노호시자오가 부러져, 실의의 밑바닥으로.
Musashi and Senhime were trying to recover Kojirō,
어떻게든 재기시켜 주려는 무사시와 센히메였지만.
why, it wasn't working out so well.
어허, 잘 안 되고 있었다.
The Reviving
지금 되살아나는
Legendary Sword
전설의 검이오
After having his beloved sword Monohashizao broken, Kojirō was deep in despair, as if his spirit was lost.
애도 모노호시자오가 부서진 코지로는 마치 혼이 빠져나간 듯 계속 실연에 빠져 있었다.
Kojirō?
코지로?
I will go-dasu !
나, 가오!
Go to where?
간다니 어디에?
It's obvious-dasu! I'm going to Amakusa Island-dasu!
당연한 것이오! 아마쿠사도에 가오!
It's just like going there just to be killed by Shiranul Clan-gowasu.
시라누이 일족에게 죽으러 가는 것과 마찬가지요.
With that kind of way of thinking, you can't do anything-dasu! Most of all, I can't stand seeing Kojirō like that-dasu!
그런 생각을 하면 아무것도 못 하오! 무엇보다도, 나, 저런 코지로를 보고만 있을 수는 없소.
Musashi. This all happened because you're foolish enough to be fallen into Kumason's trap. I did not wanted to join.
무사시. 네가 바보라서 쿠마손의 함정에 빠져서 이렇게 된 것이다. 난 싫었다.
It's all Musashi's fault. Musashi was wrong.
무사시 잘못이다. 무사시 잘못.
Is he not recoverable-gowasu?
재기 불능인가.
Even if I apologize, he'll going to blame me forever-dasu.
사과해도 언제까지나 날 원망할 생각이오.
Monohoshizao was truly like his other self.
모노호시자오는 정말로 자신의 분신 같은 것이었으니 말이야.
That's why I'm going to be responsible and go to Amakusa Island to find that secret sword on a par with Monohoshizao!
그러니까 책임을 지고 내가 모노호시자오에 견줄 비검을 아마쿠사도에 찾으러 가오!
Wait, Musashi. I understand you, but it's too dangerous.
잠깐, 무사시. 마음은 알겠는데 위험해.
Oh, but I must go-dasu. Do not stop me-dasu! Unhand me-dasu!
아, 나는 가야만 하오. 막지 마시오, 오센짱! 그 손을 놓으시오!
Unhand me! Unhand me! Let me go-dasu!
놓아! 놓아! 놓으시오!
I didn't hold you at the first place.
애초에 안 잡았어.
Idiot.
바보 자식.
Huh?
어라?
This is just right-dasu! I'll borrow this ship-dasu!
마침 딱 잘 됐소. 이 배 빌리겠소!
Musashi!
무사시!
Everything is Musashi's fault.
모든 건 무사시 잘못입니다.
How noisy-dasu...
시끄럽소...
Musashi! It's your fault. Musashi! Musashi!
무사시. 네 잘못이다. 무사시! 무사시!
Kojirō, please forgive me-dasu...
코지로, 용서해 주시오...
It was just a dream-dasu...
꿈이었소...
Ouch! That hurts-dasu! Waaah! Help me!
아야! 아프오! 으악! 살려주시오!
That hurt...
아팠소...
This must be that Amakusa Island-dasu. I don't feel anything suspicious-dasu...
여기가 아마쿠사 섬이오. 수상한 분위기는 어디에도 없소...
I just remembered that I didn't eat anything since last night-dasu.
그러고 보니 어젯밤부터 아무것도 안 먹었소.
Excuse me-dasu! Is there a dango house around here-dasu?
실례하오! 이 주변에 단고집 있소?
Hello-dasu?
누구 있소?
Absent, I guess...
외출이오...
Excuse me-dasu! Is there a dango house around here-dasu?
실례하오! 이 주변에 단고집 있소?
I'm gonna die of hunger-dasu...
나, 배고파서 죽을 것 같소.
Is anyone there-dasu?!
누구 있소?!
Wait for me-dasu!
잠깐 기다리시오!
W- where did they go-dasu?
어, 어디 갔소...
I'm too hungry to move-dasu.
아, 배고파서 못 움직이오.
Anybody there-dasu?!
누구 있소?!
I want to eat anything possible-dasu! Please!
나, 아무거나 좋으니까 먹고 싶소! 꼭!
Who's there-dasu?!
누구이오!
It looks like a trap-dasu. I'm surrounded by enemies-dasu!
함정인 것 같소. 나, 적에게 둘러싸였소!
Stop it-dasu!
관두시오!
Give my daddy and mommy back!
아빠 엄마 돌려줘!
We'll get rid of any Shiranui Clan!
시라누이 일족 따위 해치워버릴 거야!
Stop-dasu! You've got it wrong-dasu! I'm here to take care of Shiranui Clan-dasu!
멈추시오! 사람 잘못 봤소! 나, 시라누이 일족을 해치우기 위해 여기에 왔소!
What? Everyone, stop attacking!
어? 다들 공격 멈춰!
Yeah!
네!
You'll know it when you hear my name-dasu!
이름을 들으면 아오!
I am the number one Karakuri martial artist of future of Jipangu, Musashi from Miyamoto village-dasu!
나, 지팡구 제일의 카라쿠리 무예가가 되고자 하는 미야모토 마을의 무사시이오!
Never heard of him-dasu!
모르오!
But anyway, he does look different from the ones who came to attack the village!
그래도, 잘 보면 요새 마을에 덤벼든 놈들하고는 다르네.
Yeah. They looked like they had ill will, but this brother has a good look!
응. 놈들은 다들 눈매가 나빴는데, 이 형은 좋은 눈매야.
You guys do have a discerning eye-dasu! I must do something for you-dasu!
너희들 사람 보는 눈이 있소! 왠지 해 드려야겠소!
Really?!
정말?!
But before that, let me eat something-dasu.
그래도 그 전에 뭔가 먹게 해 주시오.
It's so good!
맛있소맛있소맛있소!
Even the leaf is good-dasu.
싹도 맛있소.
We eat much, but I never saw someone who eat as much as Musashi bro!
우리도 잘 먹긴 하는데, 무사시 형처럼 먹는 사람은 처음 봐.
Really. He already ate 20!
정말. 벌써 20개 째야.
Oh, right. Is there any legendary secret sword in this island-dasu?
아, 그렇소. 이 섬에 전설의 비검이 있소?
By that legendary secret sword, do you mean Hououmaru?
전설의 비검? 그거, 봉황환 말이야?
So that was Hououmaru! Where is it?
봉황환이었소! 어디 있소?
My dad was taking care of it preciously, but then Shiranui Clan took it.
우리 아빠가 소중하게 관리하고 있었는데 시라누이 일족이 가져갔어.
-What-dasu?! -About a month ago.
-뭣이오?! -한 달 정도 전에.
Shiranui Clan has appeared to take all the people on the island, and in addition, they took all the swords, hoes, and spades.
시라누이 일족이 나타나 섬에 있는 모든 사람을 데려가고, 게다가 칼, 괭이, 쟁기 따위를 죄다 빼앗아가 버렸어.
During that, we somehow escaped and we're here.
그 때, 어떻게든 우린 도망쳐서 살았어.
So that's what happened-dasu.
그랬소.
I wonder where did that Shiranui Clan take my mommy to...
시라누이 일족은 우리 엄마를 어디로 데려갔을까...
Daddy! Mommy!
아빠! 엄마!
Ikazuchi
이카즈치
I am one of Shiranui Clan, Ikazuchi!
나는 시라누이 일족의 이카즈치다.
I am Musashi, the future number one martial artist of Jipangu!
나는 지팡구 제일의 무예가가 될 무사시이오!
Huh?
어라?
Musashi. You are here to rush to your doom!
무사시. 날아 불에 들어오는 여름의 벌레는 네놈을 말하는구나!
Shut up-dasu! Where did you take the villagers-dasu?!
시끄럽소! 마을 사람들을 어디에 데려갔소!
Wanna know?
알고 싶냐?
Of course-dasu!
당연하오!
I won't free them, but I'll let you know where they are.
돌려 주진 않을 테지만 어디 있는지는 보여 주지.
Run away while I fight-dasu.
내가 싸울 동안 도망치시오.
Got it. Are you really okay by yourself?
알았어. 형 혼자 괜찮아?
Of course-dasu!
당연하오!
I'll show you Ikazuchi Shell!
이카즈치 탄을 보여 주겠다!
The sky called and the ground called Musashi, the man who will take care of all the evil in this world!
하늘이 부르고 땅이 불렀소! 이 세상의 악을 퇴치할 사내 무사시!
I'm here to fight-dasu.
지금 등장하오.
Niten'ichiryū: Iron Windmill!
이천일류 철풍차!
Aren't you an impudent brat?! Take my Ikazuchi Shell!
음? 건방진 꼬맹이가! 이카즈치 탄을 맛보아라!
Prepare yourself!
각오해라!
This must be the secret factory of Shiranui Clan.
여긴 시라누이 일족의 비밀 공장이오.
Damn!
젠장!
I showed them as promised. The villagers are in underground of the island!
약속대로 보여줬다. 섬 지하에 있는 마을 사람들을!
Why would you make them work in a place like this-dasu?!
이런 곳에서 일이나 시키고 대체 뭘 꾸미고 있소!
Take a look at that!
저걸 봐라!
We are making new type cannons and guns.
신식 대포, 철포를 만들고 있다.
Huh? That many?
어? 저렇게 잔뜩?
With that many, it is trivial to annihilate Edotopia!
저만큼 있으면 에도토피아를 전멸하는 것도 아주 쉽다!
Meaning that the world is under Shiranui Clan's hands!
즉, 천하는 우리 시라누이 일족의 것이다!
I won't let that happen-dasu! I'll stop you-dasu!
그렇게 되도록 냅둘 것 같소이까! 이 내가 그렇게 하도록 안 두오!
But Musashi, you can't do anything if you die, no matter how deeply you desire.
그렇지만 무사시, 아무리 의지가 있어도 죽으면 아무것도 못 한다.
What?!
뭣이오?!
This gun was just made. I will test its might by shooting this to you!
이건 막 만들어진 철포다. 이 위력을 네게 쏘아 시험해 주마!
Wah! You don't have to test that to find it out!
으악! 그런 건 시험해 보지 않아도 괜찮소!
Hope you're prepared!
각오해라!
I won't!
안 하오!
Will Musashi finally lose his life?! Wait for the stormy latter half!
결국 목숨을 잃는가, 무사시! 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
I got hit!
당했소!
Hm? I didn't charge it with ammo.
어? 총알을 넣지 않았군.
What did you say-dasu?! I tried hard to prepare-dasu! Hurry up and shoot-dasu!
뭣이오?! 기껏 각오했더니! 어서 쏘시오!
Don't worry! You're going to hell soon!
걱정 마라! 지금 곧 저 세상에 보내 주마!
Understand this! You're going this time!
알겠냐! 이번에야말로 간다!
Who's that?!
누구냐!
Hm? You bastard!
음? 네놈은!
Mr. Jūbee!
주베 씨!
What? Jūbee?
뭐? 주베?
I've seen Shiranui Clan's secret weapon factory for sure!
시라누이 일족의 비밀 병기 공장. 단단히 봐 두었다!
Ieyasu's underling! How did you sneak in?! Anyway, know that your life ends now!
이에야스의 개자식! 어느새 몰래 들어왔나! 그렇지만 네 명줄도 여기까지인 줄 알아라!
Thank you, Mr. Jūbee!
주베 씨, 고맙소!
How dare you, you bastard?! Take this!
이 자식이! 먹어라!
Prepare yourself!
각오해라!
Stop! I'll face you!
멈춰라! 넌 내가 상대한다!
Hmph! Just as I wanted!
흥! 바라던 바라!
-What a fool. -What?!
-멍청한 자식. -뭐?!
I'll fight too-dasu!
나도 하오!
That's as far as you go, Musashi, Jūbee!
거기까지다! 무사시! 주베!
If you don't want to kill the villagers, then put your sword down!
마을 사람들을 죽이기 싫다면 칼을 내려두어라!
H- how cowardly!
비, 비겁하오!
There's no coward or whatsoever in a battle! Whoever is smarter wins, and that's it!
전투에 비겁하고 자시고 하는 거 없다! 머리 좋은 놈이 이길 뿐이다!
We have no choice.
어쩔 수 없군.
There is no need to put your swords down-gowasu!
칼을 내려둘 필요는 없소!
Osenchan! Mr. Saigo! Kojirō! How did you get here?!
오센짱! 사이고 씨! 코지로! 어째서 여기에!
We were worried about you, Musashi, especially since you're alone!
무사시 혼자서는 걱정되니까 왔어!
Now, now, Shiranui, put your weapons down-gowasu.
자, 시라누이 군, 순순히 무기를 내려두시오.
Too bad. You're the ones to give up with futile actions.
안됐군. 이라고 하고 싶던 참이지만 그쪽이야말로 헛짓은 관둬라.
Futile actions-gowasu?
헛짓이오?
That's right! There's no ammo in those guns yet!
그렇다! 그 철포에는 아직 총알이 들어가 있지 않다!
What did you say?! Well, that's bad-gowasu...
뭣이?! 곤란하오...
It's all Musashi's fault.
모두 무사시 탓이다.
Being able to send Saigo, Kojirō, and Senhime along with them to the other world is truly a joyous occasion!
사이고, 코지로, 센히메도 한꺼번에 저 세상에 보낼 수 있다니 경사스러운 일이로다!
Go get them!
자, 저 놈들을 포박해라!
W- what's going on?!
뭐, 뭔 일이냐, 대체?!
Musashi bro, we're here to save you!
무사시 형, 구하러 왔어!
Thank you-dasu!
오, 고맙소!
Mr. Musashi, why not rage around again?
무사시 님, 다시 한번 날뛰어 봅시다!
You're right!
그렇소!
Mr. Saigo, deal with those Shiranuis using this chance!
사이고 씨, 이 틈에 시라누이를 처리해!
Understood!
알겠소!
Everyone's so energetic...
다들 활기차구나...
Chest!
체스트!
Bro, we took your swords!
형, 칼 가져왔어!
Thank you-dasu!
고맙소!
Ichirota!
이치로타!
Dad! Mom!
아빠! 엄마!
I wanted to see you!
보고 싶었어!
Are everyone alright?
다들 괜찮구나.
You must be Ichirota's father-dasu! What a relief-dasu!
이치로타의 아버지이오! 잘 됐소!
By the way, is that legendary secret sword Hououmaru alright-dasu, or did it become scrap iron-dasu?
그나저나, 전설의 비검 봉황환은 괜찮소, 아니면 쇠 부스러기가 되어 버렸소?
Hououmaru is hidden and safe.
봉황환만은 숨겨 두었습니다.
Great to know-dasu! I'd like you to give that to Kojirō-dasu.
잘 됐소! 꼭 코지로에게 양도해 주시면 좋겠소!
If Mr. Kojirō has a qualifying capacity to have one, then I can...
만약 코지로 님에게 가질 자격이 될 능력이 있다면 괜찮습니다만...
Huh? What is that capacity-dasu?
어? 그 능력이 뭣이오?
Until now, numerous martial artists came, looking for Hououmaru, but nobody has ever managed to take it out.
지금까지 수많은 무예가가 봉황환을 보고 오셨지만, 지금까지 그 누구 하나 빼내지 못했습니다.
The sword's stuck-dasu...
칼이 안 빠지오?
If Kojirō can pull it out, can he have it-dasu?
만약 코지로가 뺄 수 있으면 괜찮소?
That's possible...
그럴 수도 있겠지만...
Shiranui has set up a fire-gowasu. Everyone, escape!
시라누이가 불을 지폈소. 다들 달아나쇼!
Kojirō! Hurry!
코지로! 어서!
We live-dasu...
살았소...
It's too early to relive!
안심하긴 이르다!
You'll all be annihilated!
몰살시켜 주겠다!
I'm tired.
아, 지쳤다.
Kojirō...
코지로도 참...
Where is Hououmaru-dasu?!
봉황환은 어디 있소!
It's hidden for now; I'll go take it!
숨겨 두었으니까 지금 가져 오겠습니다!
Please do so-dasu!
부탁드리오!
Chest!
체스트!
Special move! Crotch Kick!
필살! 가랑이 차기!
Did that hurt?
아파?
Pretty tough, eh?!
만만찮은 놈들이군!
Shiranui Magic, Ikazuchi Shell!
시라누이 요술 이카즈치 탄!
Mr. Jūbee! Mr. Saigo!
주베 씨! 사이고 씨!
Mr. Musashi! I took Hououmaru!
무사시 씨! 봉황환을 가져왔습니다!
Watch out-dasu!
조심하시오!
Kojirō's back to his original beautiful look!
원래의 화려하고 아름다운 코지로로 돌아왔어!
He pulled out Hououmaru-dasu!
봉황환이 빠졌소!
Shiranui Magic, Ikazuchi Shell!
시라누이 요술 이카즈치 탄!
Kojirō! Watch out-dasu!
코지로! 위험하오!
W- what are you doing?!
뭐, 뭔 짓이냐!
He woke up! Kojirō, are you alright?
정신 차렸어! 코지로, 괜찮아?
What a relief-dasu!
잘 됐소!
W- what... was I doing?
나, 난 대체... 어째서...
You were unconscious for numerous hours. We were so worried!
몇 시간이고 정신을 잃어서 걱정했어.
The legends of Amakusa Island say that the one to pull out Hououmaru and
봉황환을 뺄 수 있었던 데다가 그 검에서 황금의 새를 출현시킨 자라면, 그 자에게 봉황환을 넘기라고 아마쿠사 섬에 구전되어 내려옵니다.
So, Mr. Kojirō, you can have this Hououmaru.
그러니까 코지로 씨, 당신에게 이 봉황환을 드리겠습니다.
Thank you so much.
정말 감사합니다.
But when the Golden Bird appears, be prepared to exhaust your mental powers.
다만 황금의 새가 나타난 때에는 정신력을 다 소모할 각오를.
Understood. I, Kojirō, will live up to Hououmaru, not only for the world and for the people, but also for Senhime.
알겠습니다. 이 코지로, 세상을 위해, 사람을 위해, 나아가서는 센히메를 위해, 이 봉황환에 걸맞는 모습을 보여드리겠습니다.
Hey, he began acting cool again-dasu.
어라, 또 잘난 척 시작했소.
But that's still better than depressed Kojirō-dasu!
그래도 그 쪽이 침울한 코지로보다는 낫소!
Agreed!
정말.
Tomb of Monohoshizao
모노호시자오의 무덤
Dear my beloved sword Monohoshizao. I could claim Hououmaru only because you were with me for the half of my life.
내 반생을 함께한 애도 모노호시자오여. 네가 있어서 이 내가 봉황환을 손에 넣을 수 있었다.
Rest in peace.
여기서 편히 쉬어라.
Musashi and others have again departed to the base of Shiranui Clan.
무사시 일행은 다시 시라누이 일족의 본거를 향해 떠났다.
But what will be waiting in front of them: flowers, storms, or a violent eruption?
그렇지만 그들 앞에 기다리는 것은 꽃인가, 폭풍인가, 대분화인가!
Sometimes the moon jumps over
허공의 주머니에 달이
the pocket of empty sky
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
Laugh loudly and
큰 소리로 웃으면
morning will come tomorrow
내일에는 아침이 와
Don't worry too much about losing
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Keep going! Go for it!
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
A bare hand is strong
맨손은 강해
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how life is! Look, a chance
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
follows us wagging its tail!
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
Osenchan sure worries a lot-dasu!
오센짱도 참, 걱정 많이 하는 여자이오.
I'm a hero, and I don't get taken down that easily-dasu!
나는 히로니까 그렇게 간단히는 안 당하오!
That's what I thought, but Genba has appeared in front of me during I was looking for Shiranui Clan's headquarters!
라고 생각했는데 혼자 시라누이 일족의 본거지를 찾고 있던 내 앞에 무서운 겐바가!
I got hit by lava shell, and into a volcano, splash!
용암탄에 당한 나는 화산 안으로 풍덩!
Next story! What?! Musashi Dies
다음 이야기! 어라? 무사시는 죽소
It's a stormy hell valley!
질풍노도의 지옥곡이오!
Next Episode
다음 이야기
What?!
어라?!
Musashi Dies
무사시는 죽소
Look forwards for it!
기대하세요!